As long as modern-day crimes involve people,
،طالما جرائم العصر الحديث تتضمّن بشراً
there are no unsolvable mysteries!
!لا توجد ألغاز لا تُحلّ
Today's case is a train trick!
!قضيّة اليوم عن حيلة قطار
Schedules are the basis of judgment!
!الجداول هي أساس الاستنتاج
He sees the single truth for what it is,
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
يحمل مظهر طفل، لكنّ عقله عقل بالغ
His name? Detective Conan!
!اسمه المتحرّي كونان
The Train Trick Murder Case
جريمة قتل حيلة القطار
Yu-no-Yama (Mountain Hot Spring Town)
يونو ياما بلدة ينابيع ساخنة جبلية
Yu-no-Yama Station
محطّة يونو ياما
Dad! Hurry!
!أبي! أسرع
Where're we going? Aren't we getting on this?
أين سنذهب؟ ألن نصعد هذا؟
No, this is the Hana-no-Machi Line.
كلا، هذا خطّ هانانو ماتشي
We're riding the one up there, the Yu-no-Yama Line.
سنصعد الذي في الأعلى، خطّ يونو ياما
It doesn't matter which one we take--
لا يهم أيّهما نصعد
both lines connect to a Tokyo-bound line
فكلاهما متّصلان بخط يقود لطوكيو
at Hana-no-Machi Station anyways...
في محطّة هانانو ماتشي بأيّ حال
We'll miss the train if we don't hurry!
!سيفوتنا القطار إذا لم نسرع
My head's pounding from this hangover...
...يوجعني رأسي من تأثير الشراب
Don't shout so loud...
!لا تصرخي بهذا الصوت المرتفع
Ugh. I don't feel up to this...
يا إلهي، لا أريد القدوم هنا مُجدداً
That was fun!
كان ذلك مُسلياً
The food, the inn, and the hot spring were all great!
كان الطعام والنُزل والينبوع الساخن أروع ما يمكن
Don't you agree, Conan-kun?
صحيح يا كونان-كن؟
Yeah!
!أجل
Thanks, Dad!
شكراً لك يا أبي
One of your clients invited you on this trip
دعاك أحد عملائك لهذه الرحلة
as a reward for solving their case!
كمكافأة على حلّك لقضيّته، صحيح؟
Yeah...
أجل
Though I'm the one who solved the case, not him...
رغم أنّي من حلّ القضية وليس هو
I'm gonna sleep for an hour until we get to Hana-no-Machi.
سأنام لساعة حتّى نصل هانانو ماتشي
What the hell?!
!أحمق
What's your problem, Sato?!
!ما مشكلتك يا ساتو؟
What's the matter? You don't need to get so mad...
الطبيب ساتو تايزو
You disgust me!
!أنت تثير اشمئزازي
I can't bear to sit with you any more!
!لم أعد أستطيع الجلوس معك
I'm going to a different car!
سأذهب لعربة مختلفة
Hey, Date!
!داتي
Aren't they--
...أليسا
Yeah, they stayed at the same inn as us last night.
بلى، مكثا في نفس النُزل معنا البارحة
Kan'etsu Medical Association
رابطة كانيتسو الطبيّة
Pardon me...
المعذرة
Ah, that group of doctors...
...مجموعة الأطبّاء أولئك
Hello!
!مرحباً
Oh, you're from last night...
...أنتم من البارحة
Did something happen?
أوقع أمرٌ ما؟
No, he's just upset.
كلا، إنّه متضايق فحسب
Where are the other doctors?
أين بقيّة الأطباء؟
We all left separately.
غادرنا منفصلين
Some took the Hana-no-Machi Line
استقلّ بعضنا خطّ هانانو ماتشي
while others took the Yu-no-Yama Line like us.
بينما البعض الآخر خطّ يونو ياما مثلنا
Both lines end at Hana-no-Machi Station anyway.
كلاهما يلتقيان في محطّة هانانو ماتشي بأيّ حال
Well, then. Nighty-night.
إذاً، عمتم مساءً
Mizu-no-Kawa! Mizu-no-Kawa!
!ميزونو كاوا! ميزونو كاوا
Huh? Mizu-no-Kawa Station?
ماذا؟ محطّة ميزونو كاوا؟
Oh, it says we can transfer.
مكتوبٌ أنّه يمكننا التبديل
Maybe we should transfer to the Hana-no-Machi Line here?
ربما علينا التبديل إلى خطّ هانانو ماتشي هنا؟
Bzzt! Too bad!
كلا، للأسف
The Hana-no-Machi train arrived here at exactly 10:30.
وصل قطار هانانو ماتشي هنا عند تمام العاشرة والنصف
That was five minutes ago. It's long gone by now.
أي قبل 5 دقائق، غادر سلفاً
Sorry to disturb you. Tickets, please.
أعتذر على الإزعاج، التذاكر من فضلكم
Here you go.
هاك
Thanks, little boy!
شكراً يا فتى
Mizu-no-Kawa Station
محطّة ميزونو كاوا
Yu-no-Yama Line Hana-no-Machi Line
خطّ يونو ياما خطّ هانانو ماتشي
Hana-no-Machi Station
محطّة هانانو ماتشي
Thank you for using the Yu-no-Yama Line today.
شكراً لكم لاستعمالكم خطّ يونو ياما اليوم
This is our last stop, Hana-no-Machi Station.
هذه محطّتنا الأخيرة، هانانو ماتشي
Please look around once more to avoid forgetting anything onboard.
احرصوا رجاءً على ألّا تنسوا أي ممتلكات على القطار
Passengers transferring to the Tokyo-bound train
الركّاب المنتقلون للقطار إلى طوكيو
will need to switch to Platform 7.
عليهم التبديل للرصيف 7
The next train will leave at 11:40.
سيغادر القطار التالي عند 11:40
Thirty-five minutes of waiting...
خمس وثلاثون دقيقة من الانتظار
Hey! Sato-kun!
!ساتو-كن
Sorry about earlier.
آسفٌ عمّا سبق
I calmed down after looking at the scenery from the very last car.
شعرتُ بالسكينة بعد نظري لمشاهد الطبيعة من العربة الأخيرة
I thought you might!
توقعتُ ذلك
Sorry 'bout that!
اعذرني
Sounds like they made up!
يبدو أنّهما تصالحا
Yeah!
أجل
Here you are.
تفضّل
Thanks.
شكراً
Here you go.
هاك
He sure has a lot of change...
لديه الكثير من الفكّة بالفعل
Well, it was nice to meet you...
سرّنا لقاؤكم
Likewise!
!نحن كذلك
Hey, Mister! Your button's about to come off!
!انتبه يا عمّ، يكاد زرّك أن يسقط
Oh, it's fine.
لا بأس
He wiped it! How odd...
...مسحه؟ يا للغرابة
Where was the body found?!
أين وجدتم الجثّة؟
Inside the Hana-no-Machi train that arrived five minutes ago!
في قطار هانانو ماتشي الذي وصل !قبل خمس دقائق
The victim appears to be a doctor!
!يبدو أنّ الضحيّة طبيب
What if it's a doctor from our group?!
أ-أيمكن أنّه أحد الأطباء من مجموعتنا؟
Everyone did leave by themselves--
غادر الجميع بمفردهم
one of them could have been on the Hana-no-Machi Line!
ربما صعد أحدهم خطّ هانانو ماتشي
Let's check it out!
!لنذهب ونرَ
Yeah!
!أجل
I'm going too.
حسنٌ، سأذهب أيضاً
Dad! What about your hangover?
ماذا عن أثر الشراب يا أبي؟
It's long gone.
زال منذ فترة
I can't stay silent after hearing there's a dead body.
لا يمكنني البقاء ساكناً بعدما عرفت وجود جثّة
Detective Kogoro Mori's excitement has been piqued!
!حماس المتحرّي العظيم موري كوغورو يشتعل
It's Utsumi-kun!
!إنّه أوتسومي-كن
So he was in your medical association?
أي في رابطتكم إذاً؟
It's Utsumi-kun. He was with us last night.
إنّه أوتسومي-كن، كان معنا البارحة
What's with that look?!
ما خطب هذه النظرة؟
I'm Chief Railway Officer, Yosuke Kobayashi.
أنا ضابط السكّة الحديدية المشرف، كوباياشي يوسكي
It's an honor to meet you, Detective Mori!
يشرّفني لقاؤك أيّها المتحرّي موري
Your cooperation is greatly appreciated!
!نقدّر تعاونك في التحقيق كثيراً
No problem. I'm glad to help.
لا مشكلة، تسرّني المساعدة
So, what was the cause of death?
ما كان سبب الوفاة إذاً؟
We won't know for sure until the autopsy,
لا نستطيع الجزم قبل التشريح
but my guess is cardiac arrest.
لكنّها كانت سكتة قلبية غالباً
If so, I'm of no use here.
في تلك الحالة فلا داعي لي هنا
Say, isn't that a syringe mark?
أليست تلك علامة مِحقنة؟
You keep quiet! Wait, a syringe?
أنت ابق صامتاً! لحظة، مِحقنة؟
Look at the vein on his arm.
انظر لوريد ذراعه
There's a needle mark with blood on it.
يوجد أثر إبرة بدم
A mark from a hypodermic needle?
أثر إبرة تحت الجلد؟
There's no doubt about it.
لا شكّ في الأمر
When intravenously given high doses of potassium chloride,
عندما تُحقن بجرعة كبيرة من كلوريد البوتاسيوم في الوريد
people can die with symptoms just like cardiac arrest.
يمكن أن تموت من أعراض تشبه السكتة القلبية
Shut up!
!اصمت
Hospitals have potassium chloride and syringes, right?
يوجد في المستشفيات كلوريد بوتاسيوم ومحاقن، صحيح؟
Wow. You sure know a lot, little boy!
أدهشتني، تعرف الكثير يا ولد
I really like science stuff!
!أنا أحبّ العلم
That was close!
...كان ذلك وشيكاً
But I don't see any syringes anywhere...
...لكن لا أرى محاقن بقربه
Which means...
...ما يعني
This was neither an accident nor a suicide!
!لم تكن حادثة أو انتحاراً
It was a homicide! A murder!
!بل جريمة! جريمة قتل
Why, you...
!أنت
You're in the way! Go outside!
!إنّك عقبة! اخرج
Alright!
حسناً
Now, then. The question is motive.
إذاً، المشكلة هي الدافع
It was a simple robbery.
كانت مجرّد سرقة
There's not a single yen left in his wallet.
لم يبق حتّى ينّ واحد في محفظته
And why are his fingers broken?
لكن حتّى أصابعه مكسورة؟
The killer was macho!
!كان القاتل مفتول العضلات
The killer held him down so hard that it broke his fingers,
أمسكه بشدّة بحيث كسر أصابعه
prevented him from fighting back, and then committed the crime!
!ومنعه من المقاومة ثم أقدم على الجريمة
Would they really go through the trouble of giving him a shot
لمَ قد يعطيه حقنة إذا أمكنه
just for that?!
قتله هكذا إذاً؟
The Hana-no-Machi line runs parallel to the Yu-no-Yama line,
خطّ هانانو ماتشي موازٍ لخطّ يونو ياما
which we took.
الذي سلكناه
The Yu-no-Yama and Mizu-no-Kawa stations
محطّتا يونو ياما وميزونو كاوا
are the only places they meet.
هما نقطتا التقائهما الوحيدتان
The train this happened on
القطار الذي وقعت فيه هذه القضيّة
stopped at Mizu-no-Kawa Station at 10:30.
توقّف عند محطّة ميزونو كاوا عند العاشرة والنصف
The question is the time of the murder...
...السؤال هو وفت الجريمة
So the victim bought the canned coffee at around 10:50?
اشترى الضحيّة قهوة معلّبة عند 10:50 إذاً؟
Yes.
أجل
We had almost arrived at Hana-no-Machi,
كدنا نصل هانانو ماتشي
and he was my last customer...
وكان آخر زبون لي
I didn't have any 1000-yen bills to give him change with,
لم أملك عملة ألف ينّ لردّ الباقي
so I gave him his change in coins, which is why I remember him.
فأعطيته فكّةً مكان ذلك، لذا أتذكره
Was he sitting by himself at the time?
أكان يجلس بمفرده وقتها؟
Yes.
أجل
And immediately afterward,
وبعدها مباشرةً
a mustached-man in a dark blue jacket and sunglasses sat next to him,
جلس رجل بشارب يرتدي معطفاً أزرق داكناً ونظّارات شمسية بجوار الضحيّة
so you got up and left.
فنهضتِ وغادرتِ
Yes.
أجل
A dark blue jacket?!
معطف أزرق داكن؟
So the crime took place between 10:50 and 10:52 or 10:53.
أي وقعت الجريمة بين 10:50 إلى 10:52 أو 10:53
That Dr. Date's jacket is reversible!
!معطف الطبيب داتي ذاك بوجهين
The other side is dark blue!
!الجانب الآخر أزرق داكن
Maybe his button was about to come off
ربما كان زرّه على وشك السقوط
because the victim had grabbed it?!
لأنّ الضحيّة أمسك به؟
He broke his fingers trying to remove it!
!كسر أصابعه وهو يحاول نزعه
So that's why he--
...لذا عندها
There's no doubt about it!
!لا شكّ في الأمر
He wiped the front of the button
مسح مقدّمة زرّه
to remove the victim's fingerprints!
!لإزالة بصمات أصابع الضحيّة
And the victim died from an injection of potassium chloride,
كما مات الضحيّة من حقنة كلوريد البوتاسيوم
which would be difficult for anyone but a doctor to get!
التي يصعب على غير الطبيب توفيرها
Plus his reaction when he heard the old man's name!
!بالإضافة لردّة فعله عندما سمع اسم العمّ
Dr. Date's probably the one responsible!
!الطبيب داتي كان هو القاتل على الأرجح
But how could he have killed someone on a different train?!
لكن كيف استطاع قتل شخص على متن قطار آخر؟
Say, aren't you going to do your job?
ألن تكمل عملك؟
Of course not.
بالطبع لا
They've got a search out for the robber.
فقد بدؤوا بالبحث عن السارق
My job here is done.
انتهى عملي كمتحرٍّ
But was this really a robbery?
لكن أكانت سرقة حقّاً؟
What do you mean, Conan-kun?
ما قصدك يا كونان-كن؟
That witness lady seems a lot richer than the victim.
بدت الشاهدة أكثر ثراءً من الضحيّة بكثير
And she was sitting nearby, right?
وكانت تجلس بالقرب، صحيح؟
Why would the killer go after the man instead of the woman?
فلمَ استهدف القاتل الرجل وليس المرأة؟
That's a good question...
...معك حقّ
That is strange...
هذا غريب
Say, why do you suppose that guy's sweating so much?
أيضاً، لمَ يتعرق ذاك الرجل بشدّة برأيكم؟
Dr. Sato.
طبيب ساتو
You wouldn't happen to know something, would you?
أيمكن أنّك على علم بشيء؟
Eh? No, not really...
...ماذا؟ ليس حقاً
I don't mind. Tell him, Sato-kun.
لا أمانع، أخبره يا ساتو
Tell him that I had a big argument with Utsumi at the inn yesterday.
أخبره أنّي تشاجرتُ مع أوتسومي بشدّة البارحة في النُزل
An argument? With the victim?
تشاجرت؟ مع الضحيّة؟
Is this true?!
أهذا صحيح؟
Yeah. It was a big one, too.
أجل، كان شجاراً كبيراً
What caused it?
ما سببه؟
An unfounded accusation...
اتّهام عديم الأساس
...that I was receiving kickbacks from a pharmaceutical company.
أنّي كنت أتلقى رشاوي من شركة أدوية
Of course, I'm completely innocent.
أنا بريء بالكامل طبعاً
Oh, man. You don't seriously think I killed him, do you?
يا إلهي، أتعتقدون أنّني قتلته؟
No, nothing of the sort.
كلا، البتّة
It's clear that you and the victim were on different trains
من الواضح أنّك والضحيّة كنتما على متن قطارين مختلفين
from what Mori-san and the others have said.
وفق ما قاله موري-سان والبقية
Yes, Dr. Date does have an alibi.
صحيح، للطبيب داتي حجّة غياب
Say, why did you take the Yu-no-Yama Line
أخبرني، لمَ صعدتما خطّ يونو ياما
instead of the Hana-no-Machi Line?
بدل خطّ هانانو ماتشي؟
I could have ridden either one,
كان يمكنني صعود أيّهما
but Dr. Date bought me the ticket, so...
لكنّ الطبيب داتي من اشترى لي التذكرة
Then what was that argument earlier?
ما كان ذاك الشجار قبلاً إذاً؟
I tried to pay him back for my ticket,
حاولتُ دفع قيمة التذكرة
but he refused to accept my money.
لكنّه رفض قبول مالي
He suddenly got angry when I insisted he take it...
غضب فجأةً عندما أصررت على أن يأخذه
I didn't know what to think when he blew up like that...
لم أعرف ما أفعل وقتها
So Dr. Date suggested taking the Yu-no-Yama Line
كان الطبيب داتي من اقترح سلك خطّ يونو ياما إذاً
and then faked an argument to move to the rear car...
ثمّ تظاهر بالجدال للذهاب للعربة الخلفية
Hey, Ran. Can I see the train schedule?
ران-نيتشان، أيمكنك أن تريني جدول القطار؟
The train schedule? Sure.
جدول القطار؟ لا بأس
Here you are!
هاك
Thanks!
شكراً
If he had transferred to the Hana-no-Machi Line...
...إذا انتقل من خطّ هانانو ماتشي آنذاك
...Mizu-no-Kawa Station would be the only place to do it!
!فمحطّة ميزونو كاوا هي المكان الوحيد لفعل ذلك
But the Hana-no-Machi train the victim was on
لكنّ قطار هاناو ماتشي الذي كان يستقلّه الضحيّة
arrived at Mizu-no-Kawa Station at 10:30.
وصل لمحطّة ميزونو كاوا عند العاشرة والنصف
Our Yu-no-Yama train arrived five minutes later.
ووصل قطار يونو ياما الذي كنّا عليه بعد 5 دقائق
The Hana-no-Machi train was long gone by then!
كان قطار هانانو ماتشي قد غادر وقتها
Maybe he couldn't have done it after all?
ربما لم يستطع ارتكاب الجريمة حقّاً؟
Wait a second! Didn't it say--
...لحظة، ألم يكن مكتوباً هناك
The Yu-no-Yama Line is Line 1.
خطّ يونو ياما هو الخطّ 1
The Hana-no-Machi Line is Line 6.
وخطّ هانانو ماتشي هو الخطّ 6
An overpass connects Platforms 3 and 4.
يربط معبر علويّ بين الرصيف 3 والرصيف 4
The stairs are right next to the rear car,
الأدراج بجوار العربة الخلفية
which Dr. Date had all to himself!
!والتي كان فيها الطبيب داتي بمفرده
Hey. Sounds like I'll be held up a little bit longer.
أجل، يبدو أنّني سأتأخر أكثر
Can you close the office up for today?
هلّا أغلقت المكتب لليوم؟
Great. Thanks.
جيّد، شكراً
A phone?
هاتف؟
A cell phone!
!هاتف خلويّ
Oh no! I left Sonoko's present on the train!
كلا! نسيتُ هديّة سونوكو !التي طلبتها مني في القطار
That's it!
!هكذا إذاً
Now I understand the trick Dr. Date used to switch trains!
فهمت الحيلة التي استعملها !الطبيب داتي لتبديل القطار
Come on.
لمَ أنا؟
If you forgot something, then ask Ran!
إذا نسيت شيئاً فاسأل ران
No! It's the killer I want you to find!
كلا، أريدك أن تبحث عن القاتل
Oh? Is it my hangover?
ماذا؟ أهو أثر الشراب مُجدداً؟
Thank you so much!
شكراً جزيلاً
This is Kogoro Mori.
أنا موري كوغورو
Would those involved please assemble in the staff room?
هلّا اجتمع ذوو العلاقة بالقضيّة في غرفة العاملين رجاءً؟
Dad!
!أبي
I've identified the real person responsible for this incident.
اكتشفتُ المجرم الحقيقي المسؤول عن هذه الجريمة
Dr. Date and Dr. Sato. Please come as well.
فليأت الطبيبان داتي وساتو أيضاً من فضلكم
The real person responsible?!
المجرم الحقيقي؟
It wasn't a robbery?
لم تكن سرقة؟
We're busy, you know.
نحن مشغولون
What is this all about, Mori-san?
ما الذي يجري يا موري-سان؟
Don't worry, the truth will become clear in only fifteen minutes.
لا تقلقوا، ستُكشف الحقيقة بالكامل في غضون 15 دقيقة فحسب
You're saying you'll point out the killer and have him arrested
تقصد أنّك ستحدد القاتل وتعتقله
in those fifteen minutes?
في الربع ساعة هذه؟
Indeed, I am, Dr. Date.
تماماً يا طبيب داتي
In other words, you're going to try to arrest me.
أي أنّك ستحاول اعتقالي
Yes. The real person responsible for this incident
أجل، فالمجرم الحقيقيّ وراء هذا القضيّة
is you, Dr. Date!
!هو أنت يا طبيب داتي
What?!
ماذا؟
No way!
!لا يُعقل
But, Dad!
لكن يا أبي
He was on the same Yu-no-Yama train as us!
كان الطبيب داتي على قطار !يونو ياما مثلنا
We can only confirm that for the first five minutes after the train departed.
يمكننا تأكيد ذلك لأوّل 5 دقائق بعد مغادرة القطار فحسب
We didn't see him again until we arrived at Hana-no-Machi Station.
لم نره مُجدداً حتّى وصلنا لمحطّة هانانو ماتشي
That's true...
...صحيح
Did he transfer?
أيمكن أنّه بدّل القطار؟
Yes. At Mizu-no-Kawa Station.
أجل، في محطّة ميزونو كاوا
At Mizu-no-Kawa?
ميزونو كاوا؟
But isn't that impossible, time-wise?
لكن أليس ذلك مستحيلاً من ناحية الوقت؟
Take a good look.
أمعن النظر
The Yu-no-Yama train arrived on Platform 1 of Mizu-no-Kawa Station
وصل قطار يونو ياما عند الرصيف 1 في محطّة ميزونو كاوا
at 10:35.
عند 10:35
Long after the Hana-no-Machi train on Platform 6 had left!
بعدما غادر قطار هانانو ماتشي !عند الرصيف 6 بالفعل
How could I have possibly transferred trains?!
كيف لي أن أبدّل القطار؟
A single phone call would make it possible.
يمكن ذلك بمجرّد اتّصال هاتفي واحد
A phone call?
اتّصال هاتفي؟
If you call from a cell phone one train stop ahead
إذا اتّصلت من هاتف خلويّ بمحطّة توقّف أمامية
and ask them to hold the Hana-no-Machi train
وطلبت أن يأخّروا قطار هانانو ماتشي
because you left something on it...
لأنّك نسيت شيئاً على متنه
10:35.
عند 10:35
Before you arrived at Mizu-no-Kawa Station,
،قبل وصولك محطّة ميزونو كاوا
you turned your reversible jacket inside-out
قلبت معطفك ثنائيّ الوجه
and disguised yourself with a fake mustache and other props.
وتنكّرت بشارب ونظّارات وما شابه
When you arrived at the station,
،عندما وصلت محطّة ميزونو كاوا
you ran up the overpass
ركضت على المعبر الفوقيّ
and headed for Line 6 as fast as possible.
وانطلقت للرصيف 6 بأسرع ما يمكنك
That's why you started an argument with Dr. Sato
ذاك عندما تشاجرت مع الطبيب ساتو
and moved to the last car immediately after the train departed.
وانتقلت للعربة الأخيرة فورما غادر القطار
You had the train employees search for a missing item
طلبت من عاملي القطار البحث عن غرض مفقود
to delay the Hana-no-Machi train's departure,
لتأخير مغادرة قطار هانانو ماتشي
allowing you to get on in the nick of time.
مما سمح لك بالوصول في آخر اللحظات
You had probably instructed the victim to sit there
طلبت من الضحيّة الجلوس هناك غالباً
before you killed him.
قبل قتلك له
I see.
فهمت
Mori-san's right; there was both a phone call and a search.
موري-سان محق، تلقّوا اتصالاً بالبحث
The man was distressed because he had forgotten a contract
كان الرجل مُلحّاً لأنّه نسي ورقة عقد
more important than his life,
أهمّ من حياته وفقما يبدو
but it never turned up.
لكنّهم لم يجدوها
Wow. But how exactly is that proof?
مدهش، لكن ما الذي يثبته ذلك؟
Was the call recorded and voice-matched with my voice?
هل سُجِّل الصوت وطابق صوتي؟
Get serious!
لا يُعقل
I was on the Yu-no-Yama train the whole time.
كنتُ على متن قطار يونو ياما طوال الوقت
Then please show us your ticket.
أرنا تذكرتك إذاً من فضلك
Ticket inspection took place on the Yu-no-Yama train at around 10:40.
أجروا تفتيش التذاكر على قطار يونو ياما عند قرابة 10:40
If you didn't transfer, then it should have a stamp.
إذا لم تبدّل القطار، فيُفترض أن تحمل ختماً
Can we see your ticket, Date-san?
هلّا أريتنا تذكرتك يا داتي-سان؟
Sorry, but I lost it.
آسف، لقد فقدتَها
You lost it?!
فـ-فقدتها؟
Would you like to do a body search?
هل تريدون إجراء تفتيش جسديّ؟
Basically, there's no proof I was on the train the entire time,
ببساطة، لا دليل على بقائي على متن القطار طوال الوقت
but there's no proof I transferred, either.
لكن لا دليل على تبديلي له أيضاً
"Innocent before proven guilty."
"المتّهم بريء حتى تثبت إدانته"
Right, Detective?
صحيح حضرة المتحرّي؟
Sorry, but I can't waste any more time here.
آسف، لكني لا أستطيع إهدار وقتي أكثر
I'm busy.
فأنا مشغول
Which platform for the train to Tokyo, again?
على أيّ رصيف كان القطار إلى طوكيو مُجدداً؟
Mori-san...
...موري-سان
Dr. Date.
طبيب داتي
Is there still something left?
لا يزال هناك شيئًا؟
You certainly had a lot of change in your wallet.
كانت لديك الكثير من الفكّة في محفظتك
So?
إذاً؟
It's entirely possible that the killer took the victim's money
من المحتمل أنّ القاتل أخذ كلّ أموال الضحيّة
from his wallet-- including all of his change--
من محفظته، بما في ذلك فكّته
to make it look like a robbery.
كي يجعلها تبدو كسرقة، وأضافها لمحفظته الشخصية
What's your point?
وما في ذلك؟
The fingerprints.
البصمات
Sorry, but Utsumi-kun was with me last night.
آسف، لكن أوتسومي-كن كان رفقتي البارحة
We both chipped in to buy cigarettes,
دفعنا ثمن السجائر معاً
so it wouldn't be that odd to find his fingerprints
فلن يكون غريباً أن تجدوا بصمات أصابعه
on the money inside my wallet.
على المال في محفظتي
He's right, Mori-san!
مـ-معه حق يا موري-سان
No.
كلا
I'm not referring to the victim's fingerprints.
لا أشير لبصمات أصابع الضحيّة
What?!
!ماذا؟
What do you mean? Whose fingerprints would there be?
ما قصدك؟ أيّ بصمات تشير لها؟
Think back.
تذكّروا
Right before he was murdered,
،قُبيل أن يُقتل
the victim bought canned coffee from the onboard vendor.
اشترى الضحيّة قهوة معلبة من العربة على متن القطار
He was the last customer, and he pulled out a 10,000-yen bill,
كان الزبون الأخير، ودفع بعملة 10 آلاف ين
so the vendor remembers him!
!لذا تتذكّره البائعة
Yes. That train vendor's fingerprints.
أجل، بصمات بائعة القطار
Dr. Date.
طبيب داتي
The fingerprints of the vendor on the Hana-no-Machi train,
بصمات أصابع بائعة قطار هانانو ماتشي
which you supposedly weren't on.
الذي يُفترض أنّك لم تكن على متنه
If they happen to be on any of the coins in your wallet...
...لو وجدناها على أيّ عملة في محفظتك
So the rumor really was true?
كانت الشائعات صحيحة إذاً؟
Yes! It's true!
أجل، إنّها حقيقية
I was receiving kickbacks!
!كنتُ أتلقى رشاوٍ
Then he caught me and tried to blackmail me!
!ضبطني وحاول ابتزازي
He demanded money.
طلب مالاً
He said if I didn't pay up, it would become more than a rumor.
قال أنّه إذا لم أدفع فلن يعود الأمر مجرد شائعة
He threatened to send incriminating photographs
هدّدني بإرسال صور مُدينة
to my medical association and the hospital I work at!
!لرابطتي الطبيّة والمشفى الذي أعمل فيه
That's when I decided to agree to a deal to get the film
عندها قرّرتُ عقد صفقة معه للحصول على الفيلم
and kill him on the train!
!وقتله على القطار
I found it hard to believe he would hand over all the negatives!
!لم أستطع تصديق أنّه سيسلّم كلّ الصور
Plus--
...كما
Someday the rumor would become the target of investigation.
ستدفع الشائعة بإجراء تحقيق يوماً ما
So instead, you planned to use an alibi trick involving trains
لذا قرّرت استعمال حيلة حجّة غياب بالقطارات
to avoid suspicion.
وقتله لتفادي الشبهة بدل ذلك
It was the perfect plan!
كانت خطّة متقنة
Like all of my big operations!
!مثل كلّ عملياتي الجراحية الكبيرة
Even the most skilled physicians are human.
حتّى أمهر الأطبّاء يبقون بشراً
Unfortunate as it may be, even they make bad diagnoses!
مع أنّ حصوله مؤسف، لكنّ تشخيصهم لا يصيب أحياناً
People are imperfect-- no crime they commit will ever be flawless!
يستحيل أن توجد جريمة كاملة لبشريّ
Wait a minute, Dad!
...لحظة، أبي
But another night does sound like fun!
!لكن قضاء ليلة أخرى يبدو مسلياً
Here we go!
ها هو
It's not much, but there's a fresh scratch mark here
إنّه خفيف، لكن يوجد أثر خدش حديث
from something thin!
!من شيء رفيع
I thought so!
كما ظننت
No question about it! This was a murder, not an accident!
!لا شكّ في الأمر، كانت جريمة قتل وليس حادثاً
The Ojamanbo Murder Case
جريمة قتل أوجامانبو
On the next Conan--
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
Next Conan's Hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Security Camera.
كاميرا مراقبة
Next episode features extra special guests.
!يظهر في الحلقة ضيفان مميّزان
Nakayama Hideyuki-san and Asagi Kuniko-san.
!إنّهما ناكاياما هيديوكي-سان وأساغي كونيكو-سان